http://www.michaelsconsignment.com/pages/privacy-policy

MY CART    0
Your cart is currently empty.
MY CART    0
Your cart is currently empty.
Home
/
Privacy Policy Michael's Consignment NYC
Privacy Policy
Data privacy is of high importance at Michael’s and we want to be open and transparent with our processing of your personal data. We therefore have a policy setting out how your personal data will be processed and protected. We are compliant with all policies regarding the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
We never pass on, sell or swap your data for marketing purposes to third parties outside Michael’s. Data that is forwarded to third parties, is only used to provide you with our services. You will find what categories of third parties under every specific process below.
For every specific processing of personal data we collect from you we will inform you whether the provision of personal data is statutory or required to enter a contract and whether it is an obligation to provide the personal data and possible consequences if you choose not to.
You have the right to request information about the personal data we hold on you at any time. You can contact Michael’s that will provide you with your personal data via e-mail.
You have the right to request rectification of your personal data if they are incorrect, including the right to have incomplete personal data completed.
You have the right to erase any personal data processed by Michael’s at any time except for the following situations:
you have an open order which has not yet been shipped or partially shipped
you have an unsettled debt with Michael’s, regardless of the payment method
if you have made any purchase, we will keep your personal data in connection to your transaction for bookkeeping rules
You have the right to object to processing of your personal data that is based on Michael’s legitimate interest. Michael’s will not continue to process the personal data unless we can demonstrate a legitimate ground for the process which overrides your interest and rights or due to legal claims.
You have the right to object to direct marketing, including profiling analysis made for direct marketing purposes. You can opt out from direct marketing by the following means:
following the instruction at the bottom of marketing emails
You have the right to request that Michael’s restricts the process of your personal data under the following circumstances:
if you object to a processing based on Michael’s legitimate interest, Michael’s shall restrict all processing of such data pending the verification of the legitimate interest.
if you claim that your personal data is incorrect, Michael’s  must restrict all processing of such data pending the verification of the accuracy of the personal data.
if the processing is unlawful you can oppose the erasure of personal data and instead request the restriction of the use of your personal data instead
if Michael’s no longer needs the personal data but it is required for you to make of defending legal claims.
Online Purchases:
We will use your personal data to manage your purchase online at Michael’s by processing your orders and returns via our online services and send you notifications of delivery statuses. We will use your personal data to manage your payments. We will also use your data to handle complaints. Your personal data will be used for identification and to confirm your address with external partners. We want to offer you different payment methods and will carry out an analysis to find out which payment methods are available to you. This analysis includes your payment history and credit checks.
We will process the following categories of personal data:
contact information such as name, address, email address and telephone number
payment information and payment history
credit information
order information
Your personal data that is forwarded to third parties is only used to provide you with the services mentioned above: companies to validate your address, communication agencies to send you order confirmation, distribution suppliers in connection with the delivery of your order, payment service providers for your payment, credit reference agencies for identity and credit checks and debt collection agencies. Please be aware that many of these recipient companies have an independent right or obligation to process your personal data.
The processing of your personal data is necessary for Michael’s to fulfill the service of managing and delivering the order to you.
Direct Marketing:
We will use your personal data to send you marketing offers and invitations through emails, text messages, phone calls and mail. In order to optimize your experience at Michael’s, we will provide you with relevant information, recommend products, send you reminders of products left in your shopping bag and send you personalized offers. All these great services are based on your previous purchases, what you have clicked on and the information you have submitted to us.
We will process the following categories of personal data:
contact information such as email address, mailing address,  telephone number and zip code
the products and offers you have clicked on
Data that is forwarded to third parties is only used to provide you with the service mentioned above: for distribution of physical and digital direct marketing by media agencies and technical suppliers. We never pass on, sell or swap your data for marketing purposes to/with third parties outside of Michael’s. Michael’s uses 3rd party vendor re-marketing tracking cookies, including the Google Adwords tracking cookie. This means we will continue to show ads to you across the internet, specifically on the Google Content Network (GCN). As always we respect your privacy and are not collecting any identifiable information through the use of Google’s or any other 3rd party remarketing system. The third-party vendors, including Google, whose services we use – will place cookies on web browsers in order to serve ads based on past visits to our website. – Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website. This allows us to make special offers and continue to market our products to those who have shown interest in Michael's.
You consent to the processing of your personal data when you agree to receive direct marketing.
You have the right to withdraw your consent for the processing of your personal data at any time and to opt out from direct marketing. Upon doing so, Michael’s will not be able to send you any more direct marketing offers or information based on your consent. You can opt out from direct marketing by unsubscribing at the bottom of each email.
Changes to this Privacy Policy:
We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, we advise you to review this page periodically for any changes. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. These changes are effective immediately, after they are posted on this page.
Contact Us:
If you have any questions or suggestions about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us at info@michaelsconsignment.com or 212-737-7273
Search our store
